Daniel Tovar

Web And Mobile Developer

Motivated and versatile software developer dedicated to building meaningful web and mobile experiences. Adept at managing project plans, documentation and implementation. Decisive problem-solver and organized leader with success handling diverse project types and sizes. Offering startup and institutional experience with the drive to positively impact business objectives and cultivate a collaborative and supportive team environment.



Work History

Address

Currently: Provo, Utah. Soon: Austin, Texas.

Phone

(808) 729-1983

E-mail

daniel@danieltovar.io

WWW

https://danieltovar.io



FRONT-FND

Mobile App Development (React Native)

JavaScript Frameworks (React, Next, Gatsby, Vue)

PHP Frameworks (Laravel)

BACK-END

API Design (REST)

Database Design (MySQL, NoSQL)

Node.js / Express.js

2019-09 -Current

Principal Full Stack Software Developer

ZooWho Inc, Provo, UT

- Principal full-stack software developer building and making product-level decisions on JavaScript web and mobile applications (React/React Native) and a RESTful API written in PHP (Laravel).
- Designed, administered, supported and monitored MySQL databases by proactively resolving database issues and maintaining servers provisioned on Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Collaborated on all stages of software development lifecycle, from requirement gathering to production releases.

2019-01 -

2019-09

Front End Web Developer

Utah Valley University, Orem, UT

- Led web projects from conception to deployment and maintained dozens of websites spanning 13 academic departments.
- Wrote clean HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP code, integrating design, extensions and third-party apps according to web development plans.
- Assembled and addressed technical and design requirements, integrating user-facing and front-end elements to maintain web presence effectiveness.
- Tested site compatibility across multiple browsers and devices, uncovering and debugging issues

PHP/Laravel

TEAM

Product Development

Project Management

Agile/Scrum

High Remote Productivity



Andres Haro – IT
 Networking Engineer at
 Dell –

hvaandres@icloud.com

Rachel Conatser – Front
 End Web Developer at
 Avalaunch Media –
 rconatser7@gmail.com

and addressing inconsistencies.

2018-01 -2018-12

WordPress Developer

PMA, Salt Lake City, UT

- Created and updated re-usable code libraries to streamline WordPress development cycle.
- Optimized speed and performance during a period of extensive growth.
- Worked with HTML, CSS, JS, and PHP in diverse tasks.



Education

2019-01 -2019-07

Full-Stack Web Development

University Of Utah - Salt Lake City, UT

- Graduated with 4.0 GPA
- Coursework in JavaScript frameworks, server programming, and database programming and design